Remember... I love you.
I love you, Thomas.
Mom!
Thomas...
it's okay.
No, no, no!
Thomas!
Wake up! We gotta go! Come on!
Let's go! Let's go! We gotta go!
You all right? You all right?
Wait, wait, wait!
Where are you going?
We don't have time!
Come on!
Get out of here!
Cranks! We got Cranks!
Gotta move! Not safe out here, kid!
Got a swarm to the flank!
Go, kid! Go, go!
Set a perimeter!
Hold them back on the right side!
Come on, kids, let's go!
Let's go! Move it! Come on!
Keep moving! Keep moving!
Tell him to take off! We're clear!
You kids doing all right?
Sorry about all the fuss.
We had ourselves a bit of a swarm.
Who are you?
I'm the reason you're all still alive.
It's my intention to keep you that way.
Now, come with me.
We'll get you kids squared away.
You can call me Mr. Janson.
I run this place.
For us it is a sanctuary,
safe from the horrors of the outside world.
You all should think of it
as a way station.
Kind of a home between homes.
Watch yourselves.
That mean you're taking us home?
A home of sorts.
Sadly, there wouldn't be much left
of wherever you came from.
But we do have a place for you.
A refuge, outside the Scorch,
where WICKED will never find you again.
How does that sound?
Why are you helping us?
Let's just say the world out there
is in a rather precarious situation.
We're all hanging on
by a very thin thread.
The fact that you kids
can survive the Flare virus...
makes you the best chance
of humanity's continued survival.
Unfortunately, it also makes you a target,
as no doubt by now you've noticed.
Beyond this door lies the beginning
of your new lives.
First things first...
let's do something about that smell.
All right!
Oh, man!
Feels great!
Frypan, how you feel over there?
Wait, what is that?
Just a little cocktail.
Calcium, folate, vitamins A through Z.
Pretty much everything
you've been deprived of out there.
Try to relax.
Sure you got enough there?
Evening, Dr. Crawford.
Good evening.
How are the new arrivals holding up?
So far, so good.
All right.
And you must be Teresa.
Thomas?
Yeah?
Come with me, please.
Thomas, thank you for seeing me.
I'm sorry for the inconvenience.
I was just hoping we might get a moment
to chat in private, away from the others.
Well...
I won't take up
too much of your time.
I really only have one question.
What do you remember about WICKED?
You're not in trouble.
We're just having a conversation.
I'm just trying to understand.
Understand what?
Whose side are you on?
I remember I used to work for WICKED.
I remember that they sent me
into the maze.
I remember watching my friends die
in front of me.
I'm on their side.
Interesting.
You say you worked for WICKED,
but they sent you into the maze.
Why would they do something like that?
I don't know. Maybe you should've
asked them before you killed them all.
I'll be sure to keep that in mind.
Enjoy the rest of your stay.
That's it?
Yeah, you've told me
everything I need to know.
You and your friends have all
been cleared to join the others.
Soon you'll all be moving
on to greener pastures.
Wait.
Others?
Hey, Thomas!
Hey, Minho, what's going on?
We weren't the only maze.
Come on.
And there was this big, loud explosion,
and these guys came out of nowhere.
Started shooting up the place.
It was intense.
They pulled us out of the maze
and brought us here.
What about the rest?
The other people left behind in the maze,
what happened to them?
I don't know.
I guess WICKED still has them.
- How long you guys been here?
- Not long.
Just a day or two.
That kid over there has been here
the longest.
Almost a week.
His maze was nothing but girls.
Really?
Some guys have all the luck.
Good evening, gentlemen. Ladies.
You all know how this works.
If you hear your name called...
please rise in an orderly fashion,
join my colleagues behind me...
where they will escort you
to the eastern wing.
Your new lives are about to begin.
Connor.
Evelyn.
Ev!
Justin.
Peter.
Allison.
Squiggy.
All right. Settle down.
Franklin. And Abigail.
Now, now, don't get discouraged.
If I could take more, I would.
There's always tomorrow.
Your time will come.
Go on, eat up.
Where are they going?
Far from here.
Lucky bastards.
Some kind of farm. A safe place.
They can only take in
a couple of people at a time.
What the hell?
Hey, Teresa?
Teresa!
Hey, hey, hey.
Where are they taking her?
They just have to run a few more tests.
Don't worry,
they'll be done with her soon.
Is she okay?
She's fine.
I got top bunk.
Too slow.
I could get used to this.
Yeah. It's not bad.
Hey, what do you think
those guys want with Teresa?
Now, if there's one thing I know about that girl,
she can take care of herself.
Don't worry about it.
Hey.
Down here.
Oh, my God.
Come on. Follow me.
What?
Hurry, this way.
Come on.
Hey, wait a second.
What the hell are we doing?
Come on, we're gonna miss it.
What the hell am I doing?
What are we doing?
Come here.
Watch.
What the hell was that?
They bring in new ones every night
like clockwork.
You know what they do with them?
I don't know.
This is as far as I've ever gotten.
The vents don't even go
into that section.
But once they go through that door,
they don't come back out.
I don't think anybody
ever really leaves this place.
Come on. We've gotta go
before somebody notices we're gone.
Why did you show me this?
Because maybe the others
will listen to you.
There's something weird going on here.
And I know you think so too.
Hey, wait.
What's your name?
Aris.
Alice.
Barry.
Walt.
Edgar.
Samantha.
I wanna know what's through that door.
Aaron.
Now, we've been over this.
You said they were covered up,
so you don't know what you saw.
- Dennis.
- It could've been anything under there.
I know exactly what I saw.
They were bodies.
Sally.
Aris said they bring in
a new batch every night.
Who the hell is Aris?
Henry.
Tim.
Well, I'm sold.
And last but not least, David.
Thank you for your attention.
Enjoy the rest of your evening.
Okay, until we know anything for certain,
we should just keep our heads down...
and try not to draw any attention
to ourselves, all right?
What is he doing?
I think he's drawing attention to himself.
Hang on. You weren't called.
I know, I'm just gonna be a second.
This is a restricted area, kid.
I just wanna see my friend.
Can you let me through?
Get your ass back in that chair.
Just remember, you are always being monitored.
Breaking the rules...
Back off!
What's your problem, man?
What the hell, huh?
Back off!
Why won't you let me see her?
Control your friend!
What's happening here?
Thomas?
I thought we could trust each other.
You know we're all
on the same team here.
Are we?
Get them to their bunks.
Get your asses in there! All of you!
What the hell was that about?
You didn't really think
they were just gonna let you through?
Nah, of course I didn't.
I'm gonna find out
what's on the other side of that door.
Right.
Newt, they're hiding something. Okay?
These people are not
who they say they are.
No, Thomas, you don't know that!
The only thing that we do know
is that they helped rescue us from WICKED.
They gave us new clothes. They gave us food.
They gave us a proper bed.
Some of us haven't had that
in a long time.
Yeah, but...
Some of us a lot longer than others.
Hey, Thomas.
What the...
You got it, didn't you?
Yeah. Let's go.
All right, look, maybe you guys are right.
Maybe I'm just being paranoid.
But I got to find out for sure.
Just cover for me.
I'll be back as soon as I can.
What the hell?
Teresa?
It's Rachel.
They took her the first night.
I told her it was going to be okay.
You sure this can't wait?
She was very specific, sir.
She wanted to speak with you personally.
As if I don't have enough to deal with.
Just bear with me.
I'm getting some interference from the storm.
Come on. It's good enough.
Make the connection.
Good evening, Doctor Paige.
Lovely to see you again.
Although I admit...
I wasn't expecting to hear from you
quite so soon.
Change of plans, Janson.
I'll be arriving a little sooner than expected.
First thing tomorrow.
We'll be delighted to have you.
I think you'll be pleased
with the progress we've made.
As you can see, early results
have been extremely promising.
Whatever it is you've been doing
to them in there, it's working.
Not well enough.
I just received board approval.
I want all the remaining subjects sedated
and prepped for harvest by the time I arrive.
Doctor Paige, we are going
as fast as we can.
We are still running tests...
Try something faster.
Until I can guarantee their security,
this is the best plan.
Ma'am, security is my job.
We're on 24 hour lockdown here.
I am assuring you...
the assets are secure.
Have you found the Right Arm?
Not yet.
We tracked them as far as the mountains.
So they're still out there.
And they've already hit
two of our installations.
They want these kids as badly as we do.
And I cannot...
I cannot afford another loss.
Not now, when I am so close to a cure.
If you are not up to the task,
I will find someone who is.
That won't be necessary.
Might I suggest we start
with the most recent arrivals.
Just get it done.
Janson.
I don't want them to feel any pain.
They won't feel a thing.
Thomas!
We gotta go.
We gotta go right now.
- What the hell are you talking about?
- What do you mean, "We gotta go?"
They're coming. Come on. We gotta go.
They're coming for us.
- Paige. She's still alive.
- What happened in there?
Aris, what happened?
Thomas, can you just calm down
and talk to us.
- She's still alive.
- Who's she? Teresa?
Ava.
Ava?
Will you just turn around and talk to us?
It's WICKED!
It's still WICKED.
It's always been WICKED.
Thomas.
What did you see?
Come on, come on.
Okay, let's go.
You guys go ahead.
There's something I gotta do.
What are you talking about?
Trust me, it's important. You guys wanna
get outta here, right? Just go.
I'll go with him.
Okay, Winston, go! Go! Come on.
You sure we can trust this kid?
You don't want to know
where we'd be without him.
What are you kids doing out?
I want this place locked down.
Call everyone in.
No one leaves until
everyone's accounted for.
Tell me you've got eyes on them.
Still looking, still looking.
Come on, come on, come on.
There.
Who is that?
Crawford. Going after the girl.
Get everyone to the med wing.
Yes, sir.
I want them alive.
Freeze!
Stay where you are!
- Why are they shooting at us?
- I've spotted them!
- They're in L-3!
- Minho!
- I'm in pursuit!
- What the hell are you doing?
Minho!
Shit, Minho!
Okay. Let's go. Come on. Let's go.
Dr. Crawford, are you here to...
Wait, wait. Okay, okay.
Where is she? Where is she!
Get over!
Get down!
- Teresa.
- Get down!
- Okay, hands, give me your hands!
- Just do what he says.
What did they do to you?
Thomas?
Give me your hands!
You're never gonna get away with this.
What's going on?
We gotta leave right now.
Come on.
Guys? They're coming! Where do we go?
Frypan! Move!
Get back! Get back!
They've got the door barricaded.
Send backup!
Okay, we gotta get outta here!
Where do we go?
Push!
Everyone stand back!
Come on!
Newt! Help, help!
Ready?
Go, go, go!
Get out of the way!
Come on, come on!
- Come on, come on!
- Get someone on the other side!
Watch your feet!
- Hurry! Let's go!
- Come on, move! Move! Move!
Thomas!
Let's go!
Stay behind me!
Shit. Okay, come on!
Stop!
There it is! There it is!
Converge on level 3.
All R-16 personnel...
non-lethal force only.
Shit. Come on!
No, no, no!
Thomas!
Open this door, Janson!
You really don't want me to.
Open the damn door!
Listen to me!
I'm trying to save your life.
The maze is one thing, but you kids
wouldn't last one day...
out in the Scorch.
If the elements don't kill you,
the Cranks will.
Thomas, you have to believe me.
I only want what's best for you.
Yeah, let me guess. WICKED is good?
You're not getting through
that door, Thomas.
Hey, guys.
Come on!
Thomas! Come on! Let's go!
Go, go. Stop him!
Shut the main vault door!
- No!
- Thomas?
Come on, Thomas! Come on!
- Move! Move!
- Thomas, what's going on?
Come on.
You little shit.
Come on, Thomas. Let's go. Come on!
Come on. Keep moving!
Come on. Come on!
Come on, come on!
Fan out!
All right, come on. Keep going!
Shit.
Come on, go! Go!
We'll lose them in the storm!
Notify on visual.
Copy that.
Standby, Two.
Be on my six.
Everybody, go, go, go.
Stay low. Stay low!
Teresa, hang on. Stay together!
I think we lost them!
Keep going, guys. Let's go.
Watch out! Where are we even going?
Come on, Aris. Let's go. Come on!
Over here!
Come on!
Teresa, wait!
No, don't go in there!
Get down here!
- Okay, come on!
- Get inside!
Come on, we should go.
Aris, get in!
Let's go, Fry.
Can you hold onto this?
Where the hell are we?
We gotta go.
- No. Thomas, stop!
- We gotta keep moving.
Tell me what's going on.
It's WICKED.
It's WICKED. They lied to us.
We never escaped.
Me and Aris, we found bodies.
Too many to count.
What do you mean? Dead bodies?
No, but they weren't alive either.
They had them strung up.
With tubes coming out of them.
They were being drained.
There's something inside
of us that WICKED wants.
Something in our blood.
So we have to get as far away
from them as possible.
Okay. So, what's the plan?
You do have a plan, right?
Yeah. I don't know.
Well, we followed you
out here, Thomas...
and now you're saying that you have no idea
where we're going...
or what we're doing.
Wait. Janson said something
about people hiding in the mountains.
Some kind of resistance or army.
The Right Arm.
The Right Arm. If they're really
against WICKED, maybe they can help us.
People. In the mountains.
Mountain people.
That's your plan?
It's the only chance we have.
Hey, guys.
Check this out.
Minho, give me a light!
Someone's been down here.
Come on. Open up.
Looks like people lived here.
Where are they now?
Let's pack some of this stuff up.
Anything you think you might need.
We'll split up, see what else we can find.
Meet back here.
Wait, Thomas.
Let's go.
Thomas.
Yeah?
All those kids that we
left behind back there.
I don't want to end up like that.
Hey.
Do you hear me?
Yeah, I hear you.
Good. Now, what are we
looking for out here?
Signs of life.
People. Survivors.
Anyone who can help us.
Does he count?
Shit.
They had power.
You all right?
I'm fine.
What?
Where did you go?
This looks promising.
Hey, Minho. Wait!
Thomas, watch out!
Get back, get back!
Jesus.
Her eyes!
Oh, shit.
Stay back!
What the hell is that thing?
Gotta move! Go!
Go!
- Hold it down!
- What?
- Minho, what are you doing?
Watch out! Watch out!
Go, go, go!
Let's get the hell out of here!
Shit.
What's going on?
I don't know.
Hey!
Run!
Go!
Shit!
Hey!
Go!
Get outta here!
Run!
Come on!
Let's go, go, go!
Let's go!
Thomas, Minho,
what the hell are those things?
I don't know. Just keep going!
Move! Move!
Where do we go?
Come on, keep moving!
- Aris, no!
- No!
Go! Go around!
Teresa!
Minho, come on!
Come on, come on!
Where the hell are we gonna go?
We gotta find a way out of here!
Go!
Faster, faster!
Newt! Newt!
Guys, help!
Newt, you good?
Yeah. Thanks, Tommy.
- Come on, Newt!
- Keep going!
Through here, through here!
Let's go! They're coming!
Guys, where are we going?
Okay, run! Go! Go!
- Just keep going!
- Come on, they're coming!
It's a dead end!
Get us out of here, Thomas!
This one!
I'll hold them back!
Harder!
Get that door open!
Move!
Come on, Frypan! Let's go!
Come on! It's open!
Everyone through!
Come on! Come on!
Winston!
Help me!
Help! Please!
Please! Oh, my God!
Go, go, go!
- Get up, Winston!
- Hurry!
Minho, go! I'm right behind you!
Let's go! Let's go!
Thomas. Get in.
Hey! Get out of here!
Are they gone?
Yeah, I think we're safe for now.
Okay, we should get moving.
Let's pack it up.
Aris, come on.
Fry, Winston. Let's go.
Hey, man.
You okay?
What the hell happened to this place?
I don't know.
It doesn't look like anyone's been here
in a long time.
I hope the whole world's not like this.
Hang on, stop.
Do you hear that?
Get down!
Everybody, hide! Hide! Hide!
Get in here. In here, in here!
Oh, shit.
They're never gonna stop looking for us,
are they?
Everyone good?
Yeah.
A little further, guys.
Those mountains, that's gotta be it.
That's where we're going.
That's a long way off.
Then we better get moving.
Winston! Hey, Winston!
Winston!
He's hurt pretty bad.
What do we do?
Shit.
Winston. Can you hear me?
It's okay.
Hang in there, Winston.
Thomas.
Grab his legs.
I got him, I got him.
Gotta find shelter!
Thanks.
It's like they're getting further away.
We just gotta keep moving.
We can make it.
How's it looking?
It's a little further.
That's not very convincing.
Hey, what's going on with you?
They did something to me.
At first it just felt like I was waking up
from a dream or something.
Then they all started coming back.
Your memories?
What do you remember?
I remember the first time
they brought you in.
I was taller than you then. And faster.
Okay.
And I remember why we were there.
We thought we could fix all this.
I think we should go back.
- What?
- Just listen to me.
What are you talking about? Go back?
After everything they've done to us.
No, it's not that simple.
Yeah, I think it is that simple.
No. You don't understand.
What don't I understand?
Everything was fine until you...
What?
Nothing.
Teresa, what aren't you telling me?
Hey!
Guys, get down here!
Winston what are you doing, man?
- Give me that!
- What's going on?
- What happened?
- I don't know.
He just woke up and grabbed the gun
and then he tried to...
Give it back, please.
Winston, are you okay?
It's growing...
inside me.
I'm not gonna make it.
Please. Please.
Don't let me turn
into one of those things.
Wait, Newt...
Thank you.
Now, get outta here.
Good-bye, Winston.
Go.
It's okay.
I'm sorry.
Thomas.
Take care of them.
I thought we were supposed to be immune.
Not all of us, I guess.
If Winston can get infected...
we should assume so can the rest of us.
I never thought I'd say it...
I miss the Glade.
Hey. Hey.
Get up.
Newt, get up. Come on, let's go.
Frypan, Aris.
I see something.
What is it? What...
You see that?
It's lights.
We made it.
Let's go. We gotta go.
Come on.
Come on, let's go. Let's go!
Hurry!
Go!
Run!
Keep moving! Come on!
Let's go!
Come on, Teresa!
Go, go, go!
We're getting closer!
Keep going!
Get inside! Go!
Oh, shi-...
Minho!
Come help him!
Come on, get him up.
Keep going!
Go!
Move!
Come on! Hurry up!
Come on! Get in.
Put him down.
Watch his head.
Who's got a light?
Minho!
- Come on, come on.
- Minho?
Minho?
Come on, Minho.
Come on, man.
There he is.
There you go.
Here you are. Are you okay?
What happened?
I think you got struck by lightning.
Come on, let's get him up.
Nice and slow.
Okay.
Let's get him up.
Think you can get up?
Yeah?
Oh, my God.
Thanks, guys.
Hey.
What's that smell?
Behind you!
Oh, shit! Oh, my God.
I see you've met our guard dogs.
Who's that?
Stay back! Stay back!
You guys look like shit.
Come on. Follow me.
Unless you want to stay here with them.
Oh, my.
Come on, keep up.
Jorge wants to meet you.
Who's Jorge?
You'll see.
No one's come out of the Scorch
in a long time.
You've just got him curious.
And me, too.
Anyone else starting to get
a bad feeling about this place?
Let's just hear him out.
See what he has to say.
Jorge, they're here.
Quiet.
Damn it.
Do you ever get the feeling
the whole world's against you?
Three questions.
Where did you come from?
Where are you going?
How can I profit?
Don't all answer at once.
We're headed for the mountains.
Looking for the Right Arm.
You're looking for ghosts, you mean.
Question number two.
Where did you come from?
That's our business.
Hey!
Get the hell off me!
Get the hell off me, man!
Shut up, you big baby.
What is that?
You were right.
Right about what?
What is she talking about?
I'm sorry, hermano.
Looks like you're tagged.
You came from WICKED.
Which means...
you're very valuable.
Good plan, Thomas.
"Just hear what the man has to say. "
Really working out for us.
Shut up, Minho.
Maybe I can reach the rope.
Enjoying the view?
What the hell do you want?
That is the question.
My men want to sell you back to WICKED.
Life has taught them to think small.
I'm not like that.
Something tells me
that you're not either.
Is the blood rushing to my head
or is this shank not making any sense?
Tell me what you know
about the Right Arm.
I thought you said they were ghosts.
I happen to believe in ghosts.
Especially when I hear them
chattering on the airwaves.
You tell me what you know,
and maybe we can make a deal.
We don't know much.
Okay! Okay, all right.
They're hiding in the mountains.
And they attacked WICKED.
They got out a bunch of kids.
That's it. That's all we know.
Yo, Jorge.
What's going on?
Me and my new friends
were just getting acquainted.
We're done now.
Hey, wait. You're not gonna help us?
Don't worry, hermano.
We'll get you back to where you belong.
Hang tight.
Going somewhere?
We both are.
Pack what you need. Do it quietly.
Where exactly are we going?
It's real, Bren.
These kids are our ticket.
The Right Arm can't turn us away.
Go now.
Okay. I got it.
Minho, ready?
Yeah.
Gotcha. Okay. One, two, here we go.
- Ready?
- Three.
Oh, shit.
In position. Send them in.
Come on, Minho. Push her harder!
Shit.
This is it.
One...
two... three!
- Yes!
Okay.
Teresa, hurry!
So what,
you're just gonna give it all up?
Everything you've built?
There's no future here.
What happens when another gang
finds this place?
And I lose control,
and I can't protect you.
I don't need you to protect me.
What happens if you get the Flare?
What am I supposed to do then?
Chain you up, watch you turn?
Put a bullet in your head?
Is that what you expect of me?
I would do the same thing for you.
Good evening!
This is the
World Catastrophe Killzone Department.
We have your compound
completely surrounded.
You find yourselves,
through no fault of your own...
in possession of WICKED property.
Barkley.
Return them to us unharmed and we'll
consider this a simple misunderstanding.
Hang on, guys.
Or you can resist...
Newt!
...and every last one of you will die.
It won't be long before
the Flare wipes out the rest of us.
The hope of a cure lies in your hands.
The choice is yours.
Go get the kids.
What are you gonna do?
I'm gonna play 'em my favorite song.
Oh, shit.
Okay. Let's go, let's go.
We're not trying to cause any trouble, okay?
We just got to get out of here.
Is that so?
Janson, I got 'em for ya.
I'm bringing 'em down.
Don't shoot us.
Come on. Let's go.
I said let's go.
You little bastard!
Okay. Come on.
Come on! Let's go!
Barkley, what's your location?
Barkley, are you there?
Sir, you hearing this?
What is that?
Brenda! Hurry!
We don't have much time!
Let's go, let's go, let's go!
Right this way!
You gotta be kidding me.
Plan B, hermano.
You kids wanna get to the Right Arm?
I'll lead you to them.
But you're gonna owe me.
Follow me!
All right! Let's go!
- Come on!
- Everyone, go.
Go! Come on.
- Come on!
- Aris, come on.
All units, push in!
They're on the top floor!
Top floor!
We're on the move!
Go!
Go, Aris, go.
Teresa, you're next. Come on.
Brenda! Where you going?
Just go. I'm right behind you.
Hurry.
Alpha 22 in pursuit.
We're on the move!
Brenda, come on. What are you doing?
We gotta go!
- I got it.
- Come on.
Shit.
Take cover!
Go! Go!
Shit!
Come on, hurry!
We're running out of time!
- On the east!
- Cut 'em off!
I got eyes on!
Here, follow me!
Come on!
Stop! Stay right where you are!
Shit.
No, we need them.
You go around. I'll go after them.
Over here. Over here.
Kid, don't move!
Brenda, where are we going?
Hurry! The song's almost over!
Holy shit!
Come on.
Thomas! Come on!
Are you okay?
Yeah, great.
No, no. How are we gonna
get back to the others?
Relax. I'm gonna get us out of here.
Here.
Why are you helping us?
Trust me, it's not my idea.
Jorge seems to think you guys
are our ticket to the safe haven.
The what?
You know, paradise.
Safe from the sun,
free of infection.
Supposedly, the Right Arm's
been taking kids there for years.
Immunes, anyway.
And you know where that is?
No.
But Jorge knows a guy.
Marcus.
He used to smuggle kids
up into the mountains.
If Jorge made it out,
that's where he'll be taking your friends.
If he made it out?
You ask a lot of questions.
Can you just come over here
and help me with this?
Please.
Well, that doesn't sound good.
Yeah.
Down here they'll be full term.
Let's go.
I think it's this way.
You think?
Do people live down here?
The Solar Storms
forced people underground.
Jorge says there's settlements
all over these tunnels.
So, what about Jorge?
Is he your father?
Close enough.
Truth is, I don't really know what he is.
He's just always been there.
And I've always done what he's asked
me to do, no matter how stupid.
So you don't think
the Right Arm is real?
I think...
hope is a dangerous thing.
Hope has killed more of my friends
than the Flare and the Scorch combined.
Just thought Jorge was smarter than that.
Damn.
Hey, I think it might be this way.
Brenda?
I'm over here.
Look at this.
What? What is it?
What the hell is this?
I don't know.
Jesus.
Go, go, go!
Oh, my God!
Come on!
Keep going!
We're almost there. Come on.
Come on! This way!
Thomas! Come on!
Okay.
- Go, go!
- Come on!
Keep going!
Watch out!
Are you okay?
Come on!
Follow me!
Yeah, I'm behind you.
Go, go, go!
- Okay, go, go!
- Come on!
Brenda!
You okay?
Yeah.
Hang on, I'm gonna find a way down.
No, Brenda, don't move.
Don't move!
- Come on.
- I can't.
Brenda, grab my hand.
No, no!
Thomas!
- Brenda!
- I can't reach!
Come on!
Brenda!
Got you.
We can get down here. Come on.
Hey, you hear that?
You all right?
Shit.
Brenda...
Yeah, yeah. I know.
Let's just go find Marcus.
Okay.
Try to blend in.
Are you sure this is the place?
You here for the party?
No.
We're looking for Marcus.
This is his place, isn't it?
This is my place.
Are you Marcus?
Marcus doesn't live here anymore.
Do you know where we can find him?
Sure, sure. He's over in Zone B.
Okay. What's Zone B?
It's where they burn the bodies.
Okay, look, has anyone else been
by here...
looking for him?
Group of kids around our age?
They had a girl with them.
Dark hair.
You know...
I think they might be inside.
Here.
Drink this.
What is it?
The price of admission.
Drink it!
Your turn.
All right.
You two, enjoy the party.
Maybe we should split up.
See if we can find the others.
Hey.
Don't drink anything else.
That was fun!
What?
Brenda?
They're not here.
Okay, well... we should keep looking.
Why?
We couldn't find the Right Arm anyway.
Not without Marcus.
Your friends are gone.
It's over.
It's just us now.
Just try and relax.
Let go.
How?
Like this.
What?
You're not her.
Brenda.
Thomas.
Hey.
Hey. Did anyone see you come here?
No, what are you talking about?
We don't have a lot of time.
Thomas, what's wrong?
I just had to see you...
and just try to explain things before...
Oh, no.
Thomas!
Just listen to me, okay?
Whatever they tell you about me, whatever they say,
I just need you to know I had to do it.
Okay?
What did you do?
I just couldn't keep watching them die.
Over here!
Come on.
No!
I'm sorry.
Thomas!
Hey, you're okay.
Hi.
We have to stop meeting like this.
Welcome back, you ugly shank.
I suggest that you talk!
You son of a bitch!
Damn it!
I'm sorry...
you're going to have to leave my house.
Looks like you've been having fun.
Listen. I don't enjoy hurting you.
Okay?
Where is the Right Arm, Marcus?
Wait, this is Marcus?
The kid catches on quick.
Are you the brains
of the operation?
I know you know where they're hiding.
So you tell me,
and I'll make you a deal.
You can come with us.
I burned that bridge a long time ago.
Besides, I made my own deal.
You're the one who taught me,
never miss an opportunity.
What's he talking about?
I'm talking about supply and demand.
WICKED wants all the Immunes they can get.
I help provide that for them.
So I lure the kids in...
they get drunk, they have a good time.
And then, later, WICKED comes in...
they separate the wheat from the chaff.
I changed my mind, hermano.
I do enjoy hurting you.
Talk! Talk!
Okay! Jesus!
But I'm not making any promises.
These guys like to move around.
They have an outpost in the mountains.
But it's a long way away.
You got half of WICKED on your ass.
You're never gonna make it.
Not on foot.
Where's Bertha?
Not Bertha.
Well, I guess we're on foot.
Get down!
Take cover!
Hey, is everyone okay out there?
We're fine.
Anyone know where
those bloody shots came from?
That son of a bitch, Marcus.
He led us into an ambush.
What do we do?
Here.
Hold this.
We gotta create a diversion.
You get ready to chuck it.
Everybody!
Get set to sprint back to the truck!
And hold your ears!
Ready? One...
Two...
Drop it.
Now!
I said drop it!
On your feet. Let's go.
Let's go! Move!
- Back up!
- Easy.
You two, over here now!
- Come on, let's go!
- Don't be stupid! Move.
Slowly.
Aris?
Oh, my God. Harriet?
My God.
What the hell are you doing here?
Sonya.
Aris, you're lucky we didn't
shoot your dumb ass.
You all right, man?
How...?
What's happening?
We were in the maze together.
We're clear, guys! Come on out!
Copy that! We're clear!
Stand down!
My God, you're alive.
Back it up, Joe!
Back it up!
We're taking them to base.
Wait, so, how did you guys get here?
- The Right Arm got us out.
- Wait.
The Right Arm?
Do you know where they are?
Hop in.
They've been planning this
for over a year now.
This is all for us.
You guys are lucky you found us
when you did.
We're moving out at first light.
Where's Vince?
Somewhere over there, I think.
Who's Vince?
He's the one who decides
if you get to stay.
I thought the Right Arm
was supposed to be an army.
Yeah, we were.
This is all that's left of us.
Lot of good people died
getting us this far.
Who are they?
They're Immunes.
Caught 'em coming up the mountain.
Did you check 'em?
I know this guy, Aris. I trust him.
Well, I don't. Check 'em.
Hey, boss...
Brenda! Brenda!
What's going on?
Brenda! Brenda.
- Brenda, talk to me.
- I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
What's going on with her?
I don't know.
Brenda, are you all right?
- Brenda? Talk to me.
- What the hell?
Shit!
- Crank! We got a Crank!
- No!
- Wait, wait!
- Step back!
- Listen, okay?
This just happened, okay?
She's not dangerous yet.
You shouldn't have brought her here!
I know.
We let Cranks in here now,
the safe haven doesn't last a week!
- Step back!
- I understand, okay?
I understand.
Just listen. Please.
Please, okay?
I told her that you could help.
Okay? No.
There's got to be something you can do.
Yeah, there is.
- I can put her out of her misery.
- No!
No!
Vince, that's enough! Let him go.
Let him go!
She's infected, Doc.
There's nothing we can do for her.
No, but he can.
Hello, Thomas.
What?
You know me?
Interesting.
It makes sense
they'd put you in the maze.
Though I must admit...
I was worried they'd kill you
after what you did.
What I did?
The first time we spoke,
you said you couldn't take it anymore...
watching your friends die, one by one.
The last time we spoke...
you gave me the coordinates
of every WICKED compound, trial and lab.
He was our source.
We couldn't have pulled
all this off without him.
Take her to the tent.
Get these guys some warm clothes.
Careful.
Come on.
Hey, it's the least we can do.
Thomas, come on.
I need to get some blood from you.
In the beginning, we were lost.
All we knew for sure...
was that the younger you were,
the stronger your chances.
You worked for WICKED?
Long time ago.
You know, at first,
we had the best intentions.
Find a cure, save the world.
It was clear you kids were the key,
because you were immune.
But why?
Eventually, we found an answer.
An enzyme produced
by the brains of the immune.
Once separated from the bloodstream...
it can serve as a powerful agent
to slow the spread of the virus.
So, you found a cure?
Not exactly.
The enzyme can't be manufactured,
only harvested from the immune.
The young.
Of course, that didn't stop WICKED.
If they had their way...
they'd sacrifice an entire generation.
All for this.
A gift of biology.
Of evolution.
But one not meant for all of us.
How long will that give her?
It's different for everyone.
A few months maybe.
But that's the catch, isn't it?
She'll always need more.
Okay.
Let's go outside. Let them rest.
Let's go.
She'll be fine.
Thomas.
You know she can't come with us, right?
He was my brother.
Hey. Sorry.
Are you okay? How are you feeling?
You remind me of him.
He always saw the best in people.
Where is he now?
I don't know.
When we were kids...
we were taken in
by one of WICKED's camps.
They gave us a bunch of tests.
They didn't want me.
They wanted him, though.
They didn't even let me say good-bye.
What was his name?
George.
That was Chuck.
How did he die?
Saving my life.
Get some rest.
Hermano.
If anything were to happen to her,
I...
I know, I know.
You should get in there. Go talk to her.
I guess I owe you, now.
So we broke out.
I'm telling the truth.
I wish Alby could've seen all this.
And Winston.
And Chuck.
He'd be proud of you, you know, Tommy.
Yeah.
Hey, Aris!
Hey, guys!
I kinda like that kid.
Yeah. I still don't trust him, though.
Hey, where's Teresa?
She went up there.
Hey, you okay?
What are you doing up here?
Just thinking.
All right, I'll let you be alone.
Do you remember your mother?
I think so.
I remember mine.
She was a beautiful woman.
Everybody loved her.
And before WICKED, she was all I had.
When she got sick,
I didn't know what to do.
I just kept her locked up. Hidden.
I thought she'd get better.
Every night, she'd make
these awful sounds, like screaming.
And then, one night, she just stopped.
She was finally quiet.
I went down to her room.
And there was blood everywhere.
But she was just sat there, calm.
She said she was feeling better.
The visions were gone.
She'd taken care of them.
She took her eyes out, Thomas.
There are millions of people
suffering out there.
Millions of stories, just like mine.
We can't turn our backs on them.
I won't.
What are you saying?
I'm saying, I want you to understand.
Understand what?
Why I did it.
Teresa...
Please don't fight them, Thomas.
What have you done?
No!
All right, drop in, boys. Round 'em up.
Go, go!
Take 'em out!
Tyson!
- Stop!
- Don't move!
Where's Thomas?
Harriet! Ammo!
Vince! Harriet!
- Come on!
- Over here!
How can we help?
You need to cover us!
Ammo!
Hey! Do you know how to use this thing?
Cover me!
This fifty's our only chance!
Brenda!
You dumbass.
Come on!
Are you trying to get yourself killed?
We gotta take cover!
We have to go.
Now, while we still have the chance.
I gotta go find the others.
No! Look! Look.
You can't help them.
Vince, hurry up!
There's too many of them.
I'm out!
Look out!
Shit!
All right, take me down.
Shit. Shit.
I'm sorry.
There's just nothing
you can do for them.
If we don't move now,
we won't be much better off.
You guys gotta go right now.
What?
They're not looking for you.
You'll be safe, but you have to go now.
Thomas...
I can't leave without them.
Go.
Good luck, kid.
Bren, we have to go. Come on. Come on.
Let's go, come on. Come on!
Let's go, let's go!
- Are you okay?
- Yeah.
Line them up right here! On their knees!
Put some eyes up on that ridge.
B-4.
How many did we get?
All of them. Give or take.
Give or take what?
Well, they lost a few.
A-4.
A-6.
B-3.
Where's Thomas?
Right here.
Freeze!
Go!
Thomas.
Get him in line.
Okay.
Bring her in.
Why didn't you run?
I'm tired of running.
Is this all of them?
Most of them.
It'll be enough.
Start loading them in.
Yes, ma'am.
Okay, you heard. Let's go!
Get 'em on!
Hello, Thomas.
I'm glad you're safe.
What the hell?
Teresa?
Wait, what's going on?
She's with them.
Since when?
Teresa's always had an evolved
appreciation of the greater good.
Once we restored her memories,
it was only a matter of time.
Let's go, let's go.
I'm sorry.
I had no choice. This is the only way.
We have to find a cure.
She's right.
This is all just a means to an end.
You used to understand that, Thomas.
No matter what you think of me...
I am not a monster. I'm a doctor.
I swore an oath to find a cure!
No matter the cost.
I just need more time.
More blood.
Hello, Mary.
I hoped we'd meet again.
I'm sorry it had to be
under these circumstances.
I'm sorry about a lot of things, too.
But not this.
At least my conscience is clear.
So is mine.
Mary? Mary?
Mary!
Mary! Mary!
Get off me!
Mary? Mary?
Mary?
No!
Mary! No!
Come on, Janson.
Load them up. Let's go.
All these people. Get rid of them.
Let's go. Let's go!
Let go of me!
Sonya! Aris!
Get back!
Everyone, stand back!
- Stand back!
- Hold your fire!
- Everyone, stand back!
- Stand back. Let 'em go.
- Thomas, put it down.
- Let 'em all go!
- You know I can't do that!
Thomas, please stop.
I made a deal with them.
They promised we'd be safe. All of us.
And I'm supposed to trust you now?
It's true. It was her only condition.
Shut up!
Everything can go back
to the way it was.
Thomas...
do you really want
all of them to die?
Listen to her, Thomas.
Think about what you're doing.
We're with you, Thomas.
No.
Don't.
- Do it, Thomas.
- We're ready.
We're not going back there.
Thomas?
It's the only way.
Thomas!
- Come on. Come on!
- Get her out of here!
You good?
Freeze! Drop it, kid!
Run! Get down!
Freeze!
What a waste.
Vince, go!
Now!
Keep going. I got you.
Get outta here! Go! Go!
Come on, Thomas! Get outta here!
Minho, let's go!
Get out of here! Go!
Get down!
Minho!
Come back!
- Thomas, get back!
- No! Thomas, no!
Minho!
Thomas!
Go! Come on!
Minho!
What do we do now?
Well, we pick up what's left of us.
We stick to the plan.
We get you kids to the safe haven.
Then we start over, I guess.
I'm not going with you.
What?
I made a promise to Minho.
I wouldn't leave him behind.
I have to go after him.
Hey, kid, look around you.
All right?
WICKED just kicked our ass.
You think about where you're headed.
I'm not asking anyone to come with me.
Thomas, listen to me.
I've known Minho for...
Well, as long as I can remember.
So, if there was any way
that we could help him...
trust me,
I would be up there standing next to you.
This, what you're talking about...
is impossible.
More like suicide.
Maybe.
But I know what I'm supposed to do now.
It's not just about Minho.
It's about all of us.
It's about everyone WICKED's ever taken,
everyone they will take.
They'll never stop.
They'll never stop,
so I'm gonna stop them.
I'm gonna kill Ava Paige.
I have to admit...
I'd like some revenge.
Well, that's a good speech, kid.
So, what's your plan?